ah what a beautiful day in Minecraft
I've just added some new mods and
Yeah I broke Minecraft I really really
broke Minecraft nothing is rendering in
at all this is why green and computers
don't go
[Laughter]
it's green and as you can see
crowned
things have escalated look at what
iskal's done and I'm now contending with
two well it looks like he's at the top
then scars in second place and I'm in
third and then there's Mumbo all the way
over here in last place
this cannot continue this needs
rectifying and I have a plan
and you may have noticed that at the
start of the video I showed you the
footage of what it was like trying to
get some mods to work well and I have
managed to get those mods to work as
you'll see a little bit later on however
I need to take you through an action
plan I have gathered lots of wood this
should be enough maybe it will maybe it
won't we're going to continue building
our house upwards just taller than this
or maybe even just short of this and
we're going to use Scar's weapon against
iscal the same thing that knocked off
the top of my base I'm going to redirect
at the top of iskal's at the same time
I'm going to build my base up and in the
same move I'm going to fire a catapult
all the way over here to land on Scar's
house here we need to make a big play
because we're actually falling a little
bit behind in this race and we need to
make sure that we remain on top although
having said that I'm not sure how much
bigger this house can get it already
looks like it's going to topple over at
any moment and I've got to say this is
probably one of the most fun builds that
I've ever had to do and I saw a lot of
people asking for a tutorial I'm not
even sure I can give a tutorial on this
this is Straight From the Heart I don't
I don't know I haven't been following
any instructions this would be difficult
to put in a tutorial form I mean I could
try I just don't know if I could do it
another thing that I've been enjoying
quite a lot is the fact that I've
actually still got the Sahara opening
music on this jukebox still it's still
like attached to my resource pack so
I've been like running around I've been
following people that still have the
reason like Mumbo and discount and I've
just been playing the song like this
okay
introducing
Green's house on top of the Sahara build
off
it works it works really well
so maybe we'll do that when this is all
finished maybe we'll play the song Oh
this is this is going to come in useful
I can I can feel it this this disc is
where did it go oh thank you lag
we're gonna have a lot of fun with this
music disc but for now it's time to do a
really really long time lapse to make
this play a reality we're going up we're
firing over
and we're taking down all in one move
let's go
and my time-lapsing ability has improved
because the replay mod has updated so
I'm going to be using that as much as
possible from now on so what are we
doing here we are of course starting off
by building up the house
taller than iskows I was going to make
it slightly shorter but then I thought
this is a real build of I might as well
go as high as I feel comfortable with
now every time I make this house a
little bit taller I always always wonder
exactly how I'm going to do it because
the whole thing looks like you could
just poke it and it'll fall over the key
for building this kind of house is
balance and explaining balance in terms
of Minecraft building is quite difficult
so one of the things I had a lot of
trouble with on this particular build is
that tower on the right it doesn't look
quite right and I will edit a lot of
this after this time lapse itself I do a
lot of editing just as I see things that
I don't quite like I'll just pick it
apart move a few bits Etc I do want
multiple Towers on this build
but I couldn't quite get it to work and
the reason is it was a two by two area
so you'll see me edit that a whole bunch
and I still didn't get it looking quite
nice but the tallest part was that main
tower there that seems to be my go-to
for the tallest part of the build off
house that I've got going this house
needs a name it doesn't have it doesn't
have any kind of name whatsoever this
style is fantastic it's like a fantasy
style build and I'm not quite sure how
you would go about making this it's just
lots of rectangles placed over each
other layer by layer and it's kind of
difficult to explain the key thing is
that everything looks like it's
supported even though you don't need to
in Minecraft you could just have them
free hanging or even just floating it
makes no difference but the key is
having everything look like it needs
each other if that makes sense then I
went ahead and detailed this at the same
time previously in the other hermitcraft
videos I haven't done the detailing in
the same episode that I built it but I
thought since I had the replay mod it
would be a lot easier to do that so this
did take a little bit of time but it
mainly involves flying around and trying
to get on the right spot adding some
staircases some uh grass to put some
flowers in and then lots and lots of
Windows and a few lanterns hanging here
or there and then by the time that all
those details were added we're left with
this build which when you take a look
around looks exactly like every other
part of the build so far but now it's a
little bit taller than everyone else's
base and it definitely looks like it's
gonna fall over part one of my
three-part plan is complete we have
successfully built this much taller than
the other buildings and we are at a y
coordinate of
190. well
190.5 that was a really slick landing on
here it's really difficult to do that so
we are officially on top of the build
off but like I said that was just part
one we're not finished yet and I've got
to admit every time I jump off this
building it's a really really long dive
compared to where it was right at the
start of this build off this is quite uh
oh it's quite a fall
well I did right click I swear I right
clicked that I mean predictable
nonetheless predictable
the house is Too Tall mate
yeah it's uh because there's quite a lot
of people online at the moment it was a
little bit laggy come on
there we go so let's do that again
right there we go that's what I was
trying to do but the right click just
didn't seem to respond anyway so part
one of my three-part plan is complete
the next part is to retaliate because
scar has gone ahead and built a giant
laser that's blasted into my building
and as you can see I haven't got rid of
the laser I haven't even turned it off
because it's it's not really touching
the build at the moment but I've got a
plan and it's going to be absolutely
genius so we're gonna do something for
part three with this laser but part two
is retaliating against scar because
iskal then came in so let's take care of
part two first what I'm going to do is
I'm going to knock off the top of his
build which appears to be the flower
here and I actually saw I had plans for
this a long time ago but I saw in the
comments a lot of you had the same idea
as me which is the build a giant
catapult we're gonna build a catapult as
part of our base or house and we're
gonna launch a rock all the way over and
it's gonna land right right on that
flower
squishing it bringing it right down
and being shorter and then the the laser
will be the top part just so scar knows
that we we can we can fight back it may
not be with giant space lasers because
my build is definitely something from a
fantasy novel but it does mean I can
still fight back
now what I need to do is find a place on
my house
somehow
somewhere to put a giant catapult I feel
like my house could topple over at any
minute I've got to be careful where I
put this catapult it doesn't have to be
massive or it would well it could be a
small catapult launching a big rock
maybe somewhere here could be good but
then I don't want to block the chimney
this is a very delicate operation I know
it I make it look easy with just
building part on part on part
but it's not it's really a delicate
balance trying to get this house to look
like it could actually stand up on its
own I mean it definitely couldn't but
I'm really enjoying this every time I'm
like no I don't want to touch it anymore
then I build the next bit I'm like yeah
we can still go taller all right so
let's build this catapult and launch a
big old Boulder on top of this flower
I logged in and spoiler alert this is
what I found the rocket that Mumbo made
had been launched all the way up
and he's added glass as flames we'll
come back to this a bit later on after
this time lapse but this is just typical
I just wanted to make my play and Mumbo
just one-upped me before I could even
finish doing it anyway I said massive
catapult it's actually going to be a
very small catapult because if I made a
huge one it would disturb the balance of
my base and would probably topple over
so I tried my best to animate this it
didn't really work out well but you
could see I built the Catapult down and
now I've built the Catapult up and now
I'm going to move that Boulder over the
top of the base where the lasers are so
imagine that I've built it down it's
launched now and now that there's me
building the frames for the the boulders
to go over so you can see that I haven't
just built a catapult and it's gone over
I've built the actual rock in flight you
can see going whoa straight over the top
and then it landed on the flower and
squished it there it's got the same
palette and everything so from this
angle it actually looks like it if you
can imagine the Catapult has flown over
and here is the trajectory of the actual
catapult Boulder Rock thing anyway so it
goes straight over through each of these
frames and then goes a Splat part two of
my three-part plan is complete we
catapulted a rock all the way over here
to land on the scars flower to be honest
with you I'm not even sure he's going to
notice the boulder wasn't that big but
he should at least notice that it's been
squished a little bit and the most
important thing is it's been knocked
down a couple of blocks so now that is
taller than this thing here so that was
part two which didn't take long at all
but when I logged on to make this
catapult
we noticed something else and that is
that Mumbo has launched his rocket and
upon closer inspection
it turns out my dastardly scheme didn't
work one little bit uh it turns out guys
I have no idea what slime block machines
do I don't know how flying machines work
I don't know how slime blocks work it
took off the wing it's taken off just
one little part of the wing and then the
rest of the rocket just went up without
it and now I'm stuck in here it also
looks like it took off the end of the
crane here as I'm pretty sure this yeah
okay so the slime block didn't care it
just attached itself to this and brought
it with it so my my scheme
to prevent this from reaching build
height which this is at failed it is at
256. Mumbo is at build height and
technically
technically it works because he's
connected it with the smoke but I gotta
say this is pretty vulnerable this looks
like it's gonna be easy to bring this
back down to earth you can't just launch
a rocket and win the build off I'm
afraid that's not how it works I'll be
honest I don't know how you win the
build off but this ain't it chief this
ain't it
I have no idea what to do about this
right now so I think I'm gonna have to
leave the rocket as it is
and we'll think of something for the
next episode potentially who knows this
thing is moving so fast because I built
this and then the rocket was launched
but we need to enact our third part of
the plan now you'll see that I've left
this laser
attacking my building but I've removed
the magma blocks all together that's
because I've got a pretty good plan of
what to do so what I've got here is a
bunch of iron blocks and this is the
closest thing I could find to a
reflective surface and what I'm gonna do
is I'm going to redirect this laser beam
up at the top of iskal's tower the laser
hits this barrier
and
will get reflected up to iskal's Tower
so to make sure we get the trajectory
right we need to work out what we're
going to hit
so this is going to bounce from there
all the way up to here so we're gonna
get rid of this and this is going to be
where it hits
I think you can definitely say that
things have escalated I'm gonna do
exactly what scar did I'm gonna take the
top of this off
just for consistency reasons we're gonna
take the top of this off and we're gonna
put that somewhere around here we'll do
that later we've got to connect this up
to make the laser work
and for the most part I think this is
going to be a huge amount of guesswork
but to be honest with you this laser
doesn't make all that much sense lasers
are meant to go directly straight and
that's it
scars laser seems to just curve as and
when it pleases so I don't think I need
to worry too much as long as these two
connect up in some capacity
but I definitely didn't bring enough
stained glass that's for sure
I think I've got that a bit wrong it no
it doesn't look too bad I need to fix
this up if I can get this looking just a
little bit
straighter but I mean look at look at
scars his has a a huge Bend in it here
so I don't think it matters too much
however we will try and make this look
at least a little bit more tidy there we
go this was a very easy way to bring
this down a notch there we go so it goes
the laser goes all the way over here and
mine is a lot less thick than this one
mine's very thin so what I'm thinking is
that you know the reflection of this has
made the beam slightly weaker and that
has absolutely nothing to do with the
fact that I'm running out of red stained
glass absolutely nothing I'm just going
to say the reflection is a little bit
weaker Yep this Iron Golem in my house
is really really annoying I got to oh
I've got to get rid of him
ah
okay he definitely can't reach me
there we go finally some space in this
house a lot of you have been asking me
to do the interior to this house but you
have no idea how much of a challenge
that would be it's such a mess it's so
thin in here that I mean I could do
something in here at least but when you
get past that point there it starts
getting really messy to the point where
I think it doesn't even fully connect on
the inside I'm not too sure
we'll add some magma blocks here and the
laser beam and there we go exactly the
same situation that Scar left us in
has now
left iscal in the same predicament so
now all there is left to do is to put
the post in the ground and then the
three-part plan that took me literally
all day will be complete and we're gonna
actually put this in the top of Sahara
here
and then boom there we go so it's flown
off the edge and landed straight on top
of Sahara in hermitville and my goodness
did this take a huge amount of time in
the space of just one episode we've
taken Scar's laser
redirected it at iskals iskal built
taller than us we built the tallest and
Mumbo fired his rocket somewhere in the
middle of it my thing didn't oh this is
really
this is really escalating quite a lot
and
now that mumbo's at Sky limit I I'm not
sure what I I don't have the time right
now to build my base all the way up to
Sky limit it takes a huge amount of time
and resources just to build it up a few
blocks at a time I've got to do this
properly but this building is going to
look actually phenomenal when it reaches
up here we now have an indication of
where the top is but I have a feeling
that mumbo's definitely not going to get
away with this right like it's too easy
it's too easy you've got to work to win
this build off not entirely sure how you
win this build off yet but we're gonna
find out but speaking of Sahara as we've
got here I actually want to head back
into the main hermit land because boy oh
boy have I had enough of the build off
for today we're now in second place
after mumbo's fired his rocket but this
is oh I'm really enjoying this either
way we need to head back to the old
lands
I can't help but feel that we didn't
make it quite clear enough in the last
episode yes Sahara is in beta however it
does work I saw so many people joking
about Sahara not being open it is open
it works this is such a huge feat of
Minecraft technology I don't fully
understand it but all of this is genius
like making a store like this that works
the way it does is absolutely incredible
so I want to just check that this works
and this being open is never a good sign
so oh there's a there's a book here
maybe I should read my own book customer
review from Rendog explosive starts got
slapped uh five out of five for design
yes quality of good five out of five
delivery time was bad customer service
was bad oh health and safety was
terrible food and cover bad
um yeah wood shop again brilliant well
that's all we need to know so hopefully
I can get this to work if it doesn't
work I'm gonna be onto the tech boys so
all we got to do of course I'm going to
be buying some Rockets because I always
need some Rockets so there's sea
lanterns now so we're gonna add more and
more stock into here as we go along so
the number of items in here indicates
the stock level so we have 22 stacks of
sea lanterns we have uh twin oh five
stacks of golden carrots we've got lots
of stacks of ice it depends on it it's
very very clever so right let's order
one lot of rockets so the rocket went in
the system
this should go on any second now
there we go
and then we need to to oh this is the uh
the time waited on here so one of the
things we're definitely going to improve
with Sahara is your entertainment while
you wait
and here's where the big old music disc
can come in handy
we take a jukebox and we play this
waiting for customer to confirm order
confirm
and now we wait
I bet that the songs the song's gonna
run out before I get my order
I could I can feel it
it's definitely on its way though we
need better feedback there's lots of
things to improve which is why this is
only in beta but there it is there are
my items
I think I wish that the customer could
see this part of it
that would be really cool that that's
something we didn't really think of the
customer being able to see everything
but that was the problem with having the
warehouse all the way over here
yeah I didn't think that through so
there goes there goes in the item and
then what we do is we come back down it
should
there we go so let's make sure my uh
inventory is empty we take the fireworks
out
it pushes it it falls back in
and then there should be a receipt here
that says Rockets one diamond
and then I pay which I'm going to do
boom we've actually made 14 diamonds
that's really cool so it may be in beta
but I have just demonstrated that the
system fully works there's just a lot of
improvements that need to be made before
we can really call it finished for a
start we're not stocking nearly enough
stuff in here
just gonna cover this up because I don't
have any white concrete but you can see
that the actual shop works and people
can come here and buy things they can
make a slightly bigger orders and
everything I'm not gonna do that because
I want other people to spend diamonds on
their shop not me
but you can see that this is a really
really clever and that brings me on to
the final thing that I want to do for
today which is start stocking some items
and I'm afraid that I'm gonna have to do
that off camera because I think I've
just run out of time for today so I will
be gathering some gravel all of tonight
probably while you're watching this very
video anyway thank you very much for
watching everyone it's still
goodbye thank you very much for watching